Privacy Policy
==============

Effective date: Mar 14, 2024

At Railway, we take your privacy seriously. Please read this Privacy Policy to learn how we treat your personal data. **By using or accessing our Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined below, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use and share your information as described in this Privacy Policy.**

Remember that your use of Railway's Services is at all times subject to our [Terms of Service](https://railway.app/legal/terms) which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Service.

You may print a copy of this Privacy Policy by clicking here.

As we continually work to improve our Services, we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Upon material changes, we will alert you to any such changes by placing a notice on the Railway website, by sending you an email and/or by some other means. Please note that if you’ve opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you haven’t provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes.

**Privacy Policy Table of Contents**

* [Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting or Disclosing Personal Data](#our-commercial-or-business-purposes-for-collecting-or-disclosing-personal-data)

**What this Privacy Policy Covers**

This Privacy Policy covers how we treat Personal Data that we gather when you access or use our Services. “Personal Data” means any information that identifies or relates to a particular individual and also includes information referred to as “personally identifiable information” or “personal information” under applicable data privacy laws, rules or regulations. This Privacy Policy does not cover the practices of companies we don’t own or control or people we don’t manage.

**Personal Data**

_Categories of Personal Data We Collect_

This chart details the categories of Personal Data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

| Category of Personal Data | Examples of Personal Data We Collect | Categories of Third Parties With Whom We Share this Personal Data: |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Profile or Contact Data** | * First and last name<br>* Email<br>* Unique identifiers such as passwords | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Payment Data** | * Financial account information<br>* Payment card type<br>* Last 4 digits of payment card<br>* Billing address, phone number, and email | * Service Providers (specifically our payment processing partner, currently Stripe, Inc.) |
| **Commercial Data** | * Purchase history | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Device/IP Data** | * IP address | * Service Providers |
| **Professional or Employment-Related Data** | * Employer<br>* Job title<br>* Job history | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Third-Party Credentials and Data** | * Email<br>* Login/user name<br>* Other publicly available information about you, such as followers and social media user names. | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide** | * Identifying information in repositories, emails, letters, texts, or other communication you send us | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |

_Categories of Sources of Personal Data_

We collect Personal Data about you from the following categories of sources:

* **You**
    * When you provide such information directly to us.
        * When you create an account or use our interactive tools and Services.
        * When you voluntarily provide information in free-form text boxes through the Services or through responses to surveys or questionnaires.
        * When you send us an email or otherwise contact us.
    * When you use the Services and such information is collected automatically.
        * Through Cookies (defined in the “Cookies” section below).
        * If you use a location-enabled browser, we may receive information about your location.
        * If you download and install certain applications and software we make available, we may receive and collect information transmitted from your computing device for the purpose of providing you the relevant Services, such as information regarding when you are logged on and available to receive updates or alert notices.
* **Third Parties**
    * Vendors
        * We may use analytics providers to analyze how you interact and engage with the Services, or third parties to help us provide you with customer support.
        * We may use vendors to obtain information to generate leads and create user profiles.
    * Third-Party Credentials and Data
        * If you provide your third-party credentials, such as your GitHub account credentials to us or otherwise sign in to the Services through a third-party site or service, some content and/or information in those accounts may be transmitted into your account with us.

_Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting or Disclosing Personal Data_

* **Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services**
    * Creating and managing your account or other user profiles.
    * Processing orders or other transactions; billing.
    * Providing you with the products, services or information you request.
    * Meeting or fulfilling the reason you provided the information to us.
    * Providing support and assistance for the Services.
    * Improving the Services, including testing, research, internal analytics and product development.
    * Personalizing the Services, website content and communications based on your preferences.
    * Doing fraud protection, security and debugging.
    * Carrying out other business purposes stated when collecting your Personal Data or as otherwise set forth in applicable data privacy laws, such as the California Consumer Privacy Act, as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act of 2020 (the “CCPA”).
* **Marketing the Services**
    * Marketing and selling the Services.
* **Corresponding with You**
    * Responding to correspondence that we receive from you, contacting you when necessary or requested, and sending you information about Railway or the Services.
    * Sending emails and other communications according to your preferences or that display content that we think will interest you.
* **Meeting Legal Requirements and Enforcing Legal Terms**
    * Fulfilling our legal obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order or other legal process, such as preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities.
    * Protecting the rights, property or safety of you, Railway or another party.
    * Enforcing any agreements with you.
    * Responding to claims that any posting or other content violates third-party rights.
    * Resolving disputes.

We will not collect additional categories of Personal Data or use the Personal Data we collected for materially different, unrelated or incompatible purposes without providing you notice. If you are a California resident, please note that we only use or disclose your sensitive personal information for the purposes set forth in section 7027(m) of the CCPA regulations and we do not collect or process sensitive personal information with the purpose of inferring any characteristics about California residents.

**How We Disclose Your Personal Data**

We disclose your Personal Data to the categories of service providers and other parties listed in this section. Depending on state laws that may be applicable to you, some of these disclosures may constitute a “sale” of your Personal Data. For more information, please refer to the state-specific sections below.

* **Service Providers.** These parties help us provide the Services or perform business functions on our behalf. They include:
    * Hosting, technology and communication providers.
    * Security and fraud prevention consultants.
    * Support and customer service vendors.
    * Product fulfillment and delivery providers.
    * Payment processors.
        * Our payment processing partner Stripe, Inc. (“Stripe”) collects your voluntarily-provided payment card information necessary to process your payment.
        * Please see Stripe’s terms of service and privacy policy for information on its use and storage of your Personal Data.
* **Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate**
    * Third parties you access through the services.
    * Social media services.
    * Other users.

_Legal Obligations_

We may share any Personal Data that we collect with third parties in conjunction with any of the activities set forth under “Meeting Legal Requirements and Enforcing Legal Terms” in the “Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting Personal Data” section above.

_Business Transfers_

All of your Personal Data that we collect may be transferred to a third party if we undergo a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other transaction in which that third party assumes control of our business (in whole or in part). Should one of these events occur, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you before your information becomes subject to different privacy and security policies and practices.

_Data that is Not Personal Data_

We may create aggregated, de-identified or anonymized data from the Personal Data we collect, including by removing information that makes the data personally identifiable to a particular user. We may use such aggregated, de-identified or anonymized data and share it with third parties for our lawful business purposes, including to analyze, build and improve the Services and promote our business, provided that we will not share such data in a manner that could identify you.

**Cookies**

The Services use cookies and similar technologies such as pixel tags, web beacons, clear GIFs and JavaScript (collectively, “Cookies”) to enable our servers to recognize your web browser, tell us how and when you visit and use our Services, analyze trends, learn about our user base and operate and improve our Services. Cookies are small pieces of data– usually text files – placed on your computer, tablet, phone or similar device when you use that device to access our Services. We may also supplement the information we collect from you with information received from third parties, including third parties that have placed their own Cookies on your device(s).

We only place Essential Cookies on our website. Essential Cookies are required for providing you with features or services that you have requested. For example, certain Cookies enable you to log into secure areas of our Services. Disabling these Cookies may make certain features and services unavailable.

To find out more information about Cookies generally, including information about how to manage and delete Cookies, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or [https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/) if you are located in the European Union.

**Data Security**

We seek to protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access, use and disclosure using appropriate physical, technical, organizational and administrative security measures based on the type of Personal Data and how we are processing that data. You should also help protect your data by appropriately selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism; limiting access to your computer or device and browser; and signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Although we work to protect the security of your account and other data that we hold in our records, please be aware that no method of transmitting data over the internet or storing data is completely secure.

**Data Retention**

We retain Personal Data about you for as long as necessary to provide you with our Services or to perform our business or commercial purposes for collecting your Personal Data. When establishing a retention period for specific categories of data, we consider who we collected the data from, our need for the Personal Data, why we collected the Personal Data, and the sensitivity of the Personal Data. In some cases we retain Personal Data for longer, if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form where that information would not identify you personally.

For example:

* We retain your profile information and credentials for as long as you have an account with us.
* We retain your payment data for as long as we need to process your purchase or subscription.
* We retain your device/IP data for as long as we need it to ensure that our systems are working appropriately, effectively and efficiently.

**Personal Data of Children**

As noted in the Terms of Service, we do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Data from children under 16 years of age; if you are a child under the age of 16, please do not attempt to register for or otherwise use the Services or send us any Personal Data. If we learn we have collected Personal Data from a child under 16 years of age, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 16 years of age may have provided Personal Data to us, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

**California Resident Rights**

If you are a California resident, you have the rights set forth in this section. Please see the “Exercising Your Rights under U.S. State Privacy Laws” section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. Please note that we may process Personal Data of our customers’ end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to our customers. If we are processing your Personal Data as a service provider, you should contact the entity that collected your Personal Data in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data. Additionally, please note that these rights are subject to certain conditions and exceptions under applicable law, which may permit or require us to deny your request.

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy and you are a California resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following rights apply to you, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

_Access_

You have the right to request certain information about our collection and use of your Personal Data over the past 12 months. In response, we will provide you with the following information:

* The categories of Personal Data that we have collected about you.
* The categories of sources from which that Personal Data was collected.
* The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling your Personal Data.
* The categories of third parties with whom we have shared your Personal Data.
* The specific pieces of Personal Data that we have collected about you.

If we have disclosed your Personal Data to any third parties for a business purpose over the past 12 months, we will identify the categories of Personal Data shared with each category of third party recipient. If we have sold your Personal Data over the past 12 months, we will identify the categories of Personal Data sold to each category of third party recipient. For the avoidance of doubt, Railway does not sell your Personal Information; for more information, please see the “Personal Data Sales and Sharing Opt-Out and Opt-In” section below.

_Deletion_

You have the right to request that we delete the Personal Data that we have collected about you. Under the CCPA, this right is subject to certain exceptions: for example, we may need to retain your Personal Data to provide you with the Services or complete a transaction or other action you have requested, or if deletion of your Personal Data involves disproportionate effort. If your deletion request is subject to one of these exceptions, we may deny your deletion request.

_Correction_

You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate Personal Data we have collected about you. Under the CCPA, this right is subject to certain exceptions: for example, if we decide, based on the totality of circumstances related to your Personal Data, that such data is correct. If your correction request is subject to one of these exceptions, we may deny your request.

_Personal Data Sales and Sharing Opt-Out and Opt-In_

Under the CCPA, California residents have certain rights when a business ‘shares’ Personal Data with third parties for purposes of cross-contextual behavioral advertising

We will not sell or share for the purposes of cross-contextual behavioral advertising your Personal Data, and have not done so over the last 12 months.

_We Will Not Discriminate Against You for Exercising Your Rights Under the CCPA_

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights under the CCPA. However, we may offer different tiers of our Services as allowed by applicable data privacy laws (including the CCPA) with varying prices, rates or levels of quality of the goods or services you receive related to the value of Personal Data that we receive from you.

_Our Financial Incentive Program_

From time to time, we may offer financial incentives, including payments to you as compensation, for the collection of your Personal Data, the sale of your Personal Data, or the deletion of your Personal Data. These financial incentives include Usage Credits, as defined and discussed in the “Free Trials and Other Promotions” section of the [Terms of Service](https://railway.app/legal/terms). In the event we offer you Usage Credits, they will be automatically added to your account. You may revoke your consent to participate in our financial incentive program at any time by emailing us at [privacy@railway.com](mailto:privacy@railway.com). Based on our good-faith estimate, the value of your Personal Data to us is related to the value of the financial benefits provided to you (via Usage Credits), less the expense related to our offering of those financial benefits.

**Colorado Resident Rights**

If you are a Colorado resident, you have the rights set forth under the Colorado Privacy Act (“CPA”). Please see the “Exercising Your Rights under U.S. State Privacy Laws” section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. Please note that we may process Personal Data of our customers’ end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to our customers. If we are processing your Personal Data as a service provider, you should contact the entity that collected your Personal Data in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data. Additionally, please note that these rights are subject to certain conditions and exceptions under applicable law, which may permit or require us to deny your request.

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy and you are a Colorado resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following rights apply to you, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

_Access_

You have the right to request confirmation of whether or not we are processing your Personal Data and to access your Personal Data.

_Correction_

You have the right to correct inaccuracies in your Personal Data, to the extent such correction is appropriate in consideration of the nature of such data and our purposes of processing your Personal Data.

_Deletion_

You have the right to delete your Personal Data.

_Portability_

You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format, to the extent technically feasible, twice within a calendar year.

_Personal Data Sales and Targeted Advertising Opt-Out and Opt-In_

We do not currently sell or process for the purposes of targeted advertising your Personal Data as defined under the CPA.

_Appealing a Denial_

If we refuse to take action on a request within a reasonable period of time after receiving your request in accordance with this section, you may appeal our decision. In such appeal, you must (1) provide sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom the original request pertains and to identify the original request, and (2) provide a description of the basis of your appeal. Please note that your appeal will be subject to your rights and obligations afforded to you under the CPA. We will respond to your appeal within 45 days of receiving your request. If we deny your appeal, you have the right to contact the Colorado Attorney General.

You may appeal a decision by emailing us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app) (title must include “CPA Appeal”).

**Connecticut Resident Rights**

If you are a Connecticut resident, you have the rights set forth under the Connecticut Data Privacy Act (“CTDPA”). Please see the “Exercising Your Rights under U.S. State Privacy Laws” section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. Please note that we may process Personal Data of our customers’ end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to our customers. If we are processing your Personal Data as a service provider, you should contact the entity that collected your Personal Data in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data. Additionally, please note that these rights are subject to certain conditions and exceptions under applicable law, which may permit or require us to deny your request.

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy and you are a Connecticut resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following rights apply to you, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

_Access_

You have the right to request confirmation of whether or not we are processing your Personal Data and to access your Personal Data.

_Correction_

You have the right to correct inaccuracies in your Personal Data, to the extent such correction is appropriate in consideration of the nature of such data and our purposes of processing your Personal Data.

_Deletion_

You have the right to delete your Personal Data.

_Portability_

You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Data that is processed automatically in a machine-readable format, to the extent technically feasible.

_Personal Data Sales and Targeted Advertising Opt-Out and Opt-In_

We do not currently sell or process for the purposes of targeted advertising your Personal Data as defined under the CTDPA.

_Appealing a Denial_

If we refuse to take action on a request within a reasonable period of time after receiving your request in accordance with this section, you may appeal our decision. In such appeal, you must (1) provide sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom the original request pertains and to identify the original request, and (2) provide a description of the basis of your appeal. Please note that your appeal will be subject to your rights and obligations afforded to you under the CTDPA. We will respond to your appeal within 60 days of receiving your request. If we deny your appeal, you have the right to contact the Connecticut Attorney General.

You may appeal a decision by emailing us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app) (title must include “CTDPA Appeal”).

**Virginia Resident Rights**

If you are a Virginia resident, you have the rights set forth under the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (“VCDPA”). Please see the “Exercising Your Rights under U.S. State Privacy Laws” section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. Please note that we may process Personal Data of our customers’ end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to our customers. If we are processing your Personal Data as a service provider, you should contact the entity that collected your Personal Data in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data. Additionally, please note that these rights are subject to certain conditions and exceptions under applicable law, which may permit or require us to deny your request.

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy and you are a Virginia resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following rights apply to you, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

_Access_

You have the right to request confirmation of whether or not we are processing your Personal Data and to access your Personal Data.

_Correction_

You have the right to correct inaccuracies in your Personal Data, to the extent such correction is appropriate in consideration of the nature of such data and our purposes of processing your Personal Data.

_Portability_

You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format, to the extent technically feasible.

_Deletion_

You have the right to delete your Personal Data.

_Opt-Out of Certain Processing Activities_

* You have the right to opt-out of the processing of your Personal Data for targeted advertising purposes. We do not process your Personal Data for targeted advertising purposes.
* You have the right to opt-out to the sale of your Personal Data. We do not currently sell your Personal Data as defined under the VCDPA.
* You have the right to opt-out from the processing of your Personal Data for the purposes of profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects to you, if applicable.

_Appealing a Denial_

If we refuse to take action on a request within a reasonable period of time after receiving your request in accordance with this section, you may appeal our decision. In such appeal, you must (1) provide sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom the original request pertains and to identify the original request, and (2) provide a description of the basis of your appeal. Please note that your appeal will be subject to your rights and obligations afforded to you under the VCDPA. We will respond to your appeal within 60 days of receiving your request. If we deny your appeal, you have the right to contact the Virginia Attorney General using the methods described at [https://www.oag.state.va.us/consumer-protection/index.php/file-a-complaint](https://www.oag.state.va.us/consumer-protection/index.php/file-a-complaint).

You may appeal a decision by emailing us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app) (title must include “VCDPA Appeal”).

**Utah Resident Rights**

If you are a Utah resident, you have the rights set forth under the Utah Consumer Privacy Act (“UCPA”). Please see the “Exercising Your Rights under U.S. State Privacy Laws” section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. Please note that we may process Personal Data of our customers’ end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to our customers. If we are processing your Personal Data as a service provider, you should contact the entity that collected your Personal Data in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data. Additionally, please note that these rights are subject to certain conditions and exceptions under applicable law, which may permit or require us to deny your request.

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy and you are a Utah resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following rights apply to you, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

_Access_

You have the right to request confirmation of whether or not we are processing your Personal Data and to access your Personal Data.

_Portability_

You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format, to the extent technically feasible.

_Deletion_

You have the right to delete Personal Data that you have provided to us.

_Opt-Out of Certain Processing Activities_

* You have the right to opt-out of the processing of your Personal Data for targeted advertising purposes. We do not process your Personal Data for targeted advertising purposes.
    
* You have the right to opt-out to the sale of your Personal Data. UCPA defines sale as the exchange of Personal Data for monetary consideration to a third party. We do not currently sell your Personal Data as defined under the UCPA.

_We Will Not Discriminate Against You for Exercising Your Rights Under the UCPA_

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the UCPA. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights under the UCPA. However, we may offer different tiers of our Services as allowed by applicable data privacy laws (including the UCPA) with varying prices, rates or levels of quality of the goods or services you receive related to the value of Personal Data that we receive from you.

**Exercising Your Rights under U.S. State Privacy Laws**

To exercise the rights described in this Privacy Policy, you or, if you are a California, Colorado or Connecticut resident, your Authorized Agent (defined below) must send us a request that (1) provides sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom we have collected Personal Data, and (2) describes your request in sufficient detail to allow us to understand, evaluate and respond to it. Each request that meets both of these criteria will be considered a “Valid Request.” We may not respond to requests that do not meet these criteria. We will only use Personal Data provided in a Valid Request to verify your identity and complete your request. You do not need an account to submit a Valid Request.

We will work to respond to your Valid Request within the time period required by applicable law. We will not charge you a fee for making a Valid Request unless your Valid Request(s) is excessive, repetitive or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that your Valid Request warrants a fee, we will notify you of the fee and explain that decision before completing your request.

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, you may submit a Valid Request by emailing us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

If you are a California, Colorado or Connecticut resident, you may also authorize an agent (an “Authorized Agent”) to exercise your rights on your behalf. To do this, you must provide your Authorized Agent with written permission to exercise your rights on your behalf, and we may request a copy of this written permission from your Authorized Agent when they make a request on your behalf.

**Other State Law Privacy Rights**

_California Resident Rights_

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to contact us to prevent disclosure of Personal Data to third parties for such third parties’ direct marketing purposes; in order to submit such a request, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

Your browser may offer you a “Do Not Track” option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and across different websites. Our Services do not support Do Not Track requests at this time. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you can visit [www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

_Nevada Resident Rights_

If you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt-out of the sale of certain Personal Data to third parties. You can exercise this right by contacting us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app) with the subject line “Nevada Do Not Sell Request” and providing us with your name and the email address associated with your account. Please note that we do not currently sell your Personal Data as sales are defined in Nevada Revised Statutes Chapter 603A.

**European Union and United Kingdom Data Subject Rights**

_EU and UK Residents_

If you are a resident of the European Union (“EU”), United Kingdom (“UK”), Lichtenstein, Norway or Iceland, you may have additional rights under the EU or UK General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”) with respect to your Personal Data, as outlined below.

For this section, we use the terms “Personal Data” and “processing” as they are defined in the GDPR, but “Personal Data” generally means information that can be used to individually identify a person, and “processing” generally covers actions that can be performed in connection with data such as collection, use, storage and disclosure. Railway will be the controller of your Personal Data processed in connection with the Services.

If there are any conflicts between this this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy, the policy or portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following applies to you, please contact us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app). Note that we may also process Personal Data of our customers’ end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to customers, in which case we are the processor of Personal Data. If we are the processor of your Personal Data (i.e., not the controller), please contact the controller party in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data.

_Personal Data We Collect_

The “Categories of Personal Data We Collect” section above details the Personal Data that we collect from you.

_Personal Data Use and Processing Grounds_

The “Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting Personal Data” section above explains how we use your Personal Data.

We will only process your Personal Data if we have a lawful basis for doing so. Lawful bases for processing include consent, contractual necessity and our “legitimate interests” or the legitimate interest of others, as further described below.

* Contractual Necessity: We process the following categories of Personal Data as a matter of “contractual necessity”, meaning that we need to process the data to perform under our Terms of Service with you, which enables us to provide you with the Services. When we process data due to contractual necessity, failure to provide such Personal Data will result in your inability to use some or all portions of the Services that require such data.
    * Profile or Contact Data
    * Payment Data
    * Third-Party Credentials and Data
    * Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide
* Legitimate Interest: We process the following categories of Personal Data when we believe it furthers the legitimate interest of us or third parties:
    * Profile or Contact Data
    * Payment Data
    * Commercial Data
    * Device/IP Data
    * Professional or Employment-Related Data
    * Third-Party Credentials and Data
    * We may also de-identify or anonymize Personal Data to further our legitimate interests.

> Examples of these legitimate interests include (as described in more detail above):

* Providing, customizing and improving the Services.
* Marketing the Services.
* Corresponding with you.
* Meeting legal requirements and enforcing legal terms.
* Completing corporate transactions.

* Consent: In some cases, we process Personal Data based on the consent you expressly grant to us at the time we collect such data. When we process Personal Data based on your consent, it will be expressly indicated to you at the point and time of collection.
* Other Processing Grounds: From time to time we may also need to process Personal Data to comply with a legal obligation, if it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or other data subjects, or if it is necessary for a task carried out in the public interest.

_Sharing Personal Data_

The “How We Share Your Personal Data” section above details how we share your Personal Data with third parties.

_EU Data Subject Rights_

You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Data, including those set forth below. For more information about these rights, or to submit a request, please email us at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app). Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your request, such as if it is frivolous or extremely impractical, if it jeopardizes the rights of others, or if it is not required by law, but in those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision. In some cases, we may also need you to provide us with additional information, which may include Personal Data, if necessary to verify your identity and the nature of your request.

* **Access**: You can request more information about the Personal Data we hold about you and request a copy of such Personal Data. You can also access certain of your Personal Data by logging on to your account.
* **Rectification**: If you believe that any Personal Data we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data. You can also correct some of this information directly by logging on to your account.
* **Erasure**: You can request that we erase some or all of your Personal Data from our systems.
* **Withdrawal of Consent**: If we are processing your Personal Data based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your Personal Data, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Services.
* **Portability**: You can ask for a copy of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format. You can also request that we transmit the data to another controller where technically feasible.
* **Objection**: You can contact us to let us know that you object to the further use or disclosure of your Personal Data for certain purposes, such as for direct marketing purposes.
* **Restriction of Processing**: You can ask us to restrict further processing of your Personal Data.
* **Right to File Complaint**: You have the right to lodge a complaint about Railway's practices with respect to your Personal Data with the supervisory authority of your country or EU Member State. A list of Supervisory Authorities is available here: [https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members\_en](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en).

_Transfers of Personal Data_

The Services are hosted and operated in the United States (“U.S.”) through Railway and its service providers, and if you do not reside in the U.S., laws in the U.S. may differ from the laws where you reside. By using the Services, you acknowledge that any Personal Data about you, regardless of whether provided by you or obtained from a third party, is being provided to Railway in the U.S. and will be hosted on U.S. servers, and you authorize Railway to transfer, store and process your information to and in the U.S., and possibly other countries. In some circumstances, your Personal Data may be transferred to the U.S. pursuant to a data processing agreement incorporating standard data protection clauses and/or the Data Privacy Framework, as discussed below.

_**Data Privacy Framework(s)**_

Railway complies with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (“EU-U.S. DPF”), the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (“Swiss-U.S. DPF”) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. Railway has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (“EU-U.S. DPF Principles”) with regard to the processing of all personal data received from the European Union in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and from the United Kingdom (and Gibraltar) in reliance on the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF. Railway has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (“Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles”) with regard to the processing of personal data received from Switzerland in reliance on the Swiss-U.S. DPF. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, (collectively, the “Principles”), the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Data Privacy Framework (DPF) program, and to view our certification, please visit [the Data Privacy Framework website](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/).

The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Railway’s compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF and the Swiss-U.S. DPF. This Privacy Policy describes the types of Personal Data we collect, the purposes for which we collect and use your Personal Data, and the purposes for which we disclose your Personal Data to certain types of third parties in the sections above. Pursuant to the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, EU, UK, and Swiss individuals have the right to obtain our confirmation of whether we maintain Personal Data relating to them in the U.S. Upon request, we will provide EU, UK, and Swiss individuals with access to the Personal Data that we hold about them. EU, UK, and Swiss individuals may also correct, amend, or delete the Personal Data we hold about them where it is inaccurate, or has been processed in violation of the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual’s privacy in the case in question, or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated. An EU, UK, or Swiss individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data transferred to the U.S. under the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, should direct their query to [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. For more information about rights afforded to EU, UK, and Swiss individuals, please see the “European Union, United Kingdom, and Swiss Data Subject Rights” section of this Privacy Policy.

In addition, we will provide EU, UK, and Swiss individuals with the choice to opt-out to sensitive data processing before sharing their Personal Data with any third parties (other than our agents or those that act on our behalf or under our instruction), or before we use it for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To request to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

In addition to any other disclosures described in our Privacy Policy, in certain situations, we may be required to disclose Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Railway’s accountability for Personal Data that it receives in the U.S. under the EU-U.S. DPF, the U.K Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF and the Swiss-U.S. DPF and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on our behalf is described in the Principles. In particular, Railway remains liable under the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles if our agents process Personal Data in a manner inconsistent with the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, unless Railway proves that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the U.K Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, Railway commits to resolve EU-U.S. DPF Principles and Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles-related complaints about our collection and use of your Personal Data. EU, UK, and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our handling of personal data received in reliance on the aforementioned frameworks should first contact Railway at [privacy@railway.app](mailto:privacy@railway.app).

In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, Railway has further committed to refer unresolved complaints under the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF to BBB National Programs, an alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your DPF Principles-related complaint, or if we have not addressed your DPF Principles-related complaint to your satisfaction, please visit [https://dpfservices.bbbprograms.org/complaint](https://dpfservices.bbbprograms.org/complaint) for more information or to file a complaint. The services of BBB are provided free of charge to you.

In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, Railway commits to cooperate and comply respectively with the advice of the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) and the Gibraltar Regulatory Authority (GRA) with regard to unresolved complaints concerning our handling of human resources data received in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF in the context of the employment relationship.

If your complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Annex 1 of the Data Privacy Framework Principles, located at [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/framework-article/ANNEX-I-introduction](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/framework-article/ANNEX-I-introduction).

**Contact Information:**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, the ways in which we collect and use your Personal Data or your choices and rights regarding such collection and use, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

* (415) 707-7675
* 548 Market St PMB 68956, San Francisco, California 94104

If you are located in the EU or UK, you may use the following information to contact our Data Protection Officer and our EU or UK-Based Member Representative:

* EU Member Representative

* DP-Dock GmbH
* Attn.: Railway Corp, Ballindamm 39
* 20095 Hamburg, Germany

* UK Member Representative

* DP Data Protection Services UK Ltd.
* Attn.: Railway Corp, 16 Great Queen Street
* Covent Garden, London, WC2B 5AH, United Kingdom

Copyright © 2024 Railway Corp.  
All rights reserved.

Product

Company

Contact

Legal

Copyright © 2024 Railway Corp.  
All rights reserved.
